<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en"><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.3.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://cxdomi.github.io/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml"/><link href="https://cxdomi.github.io/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en"/><updated>2024-10-07T22:01:37+00:00</updated><id>https://cxdomi.github.io/feed.xml</id><title type="html">blank</title><subtitle>Personal public history portfolio website for Cristian Dominguez. </subtitle><entry><title type="html">Public Historian vol. 45, no. 4 (Nov. 2023) review</title><link href="https://cxdomi.github.io/blog/2024/pubhist-review/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Public Historian vol. 45, no. 4 (Nov. 2023) review"/><published>2024-10-07T18:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-10-07T18:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://cxdomi.github.io/blog/2024/pubhist-review</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://cxdomi.github.io/blog/2024/pubhist-review/"><![CDATA[<p>This issue of The Public Historian from November 2023 is organized around the theme of digital archives. In addition to exhibition and book reviews, the issue features five “reports from the field,” three of which directly relate to digital archives, while the other two detail instances of public historian work. Overall, the issue demonstrates the growing significance of technology in the daily practice of public historians and the benefits digital approaches bring to developing more responsive, representative, and accessible histories among the public.</p> <p>The first article, “Slow Disasters and Adaptive Archiving: COVID-19 and the Rolling-Response Model,” details the creation of a digital archive project led by Arizona State University to document individual experiences of the COVID-19 global pandemic. Dubbed “Journal of the Plague Year: A COVID-19 Archive,” the project originally aimed to document student experiences of a single disrupted semester, but changed scope as the pandemic evolved into subsequent stages to collect stories from multiple locales and demographics. In doing so, they moved from a “rapid-response model,” covering the immediate response to an event, to a “rolling-response model,” coined by the authors, that spans six months or more and enables historians to “engage in a constant feedback loop” that can fill silences in the record, respond to discursive challenges, and more accurately reflect less discrete and definable events, like pandemics.</p> <p>The second article, “Increasing Access to American Indian Off-Reservation Boarding School Archives: Sherman Indian Museum Digital Project,” documents a more straightforward digital archive project, in which University of California-Riverside built on a trusted relationship with the Sherman Indian Museum to digitize their collections, fund equipment upgrades, and increase the accessibility of their catalog to anyone interested in learning about the checkered history of native boarding schools. The key difference with a standard digital archive project is a move away from values of content ownership and open access to greater sensitivity towards indigenous cultural artifacts as specified by the Protocols for Native American Archival Materials (PNAAM). Following this protocol, UC-R successfully advocated to the proper organizations for updates to archiving software that have made digital archives more culturally inclusive.</p> <p>The third article, “History, Historical Culture, and 1821: Creating a Digital Archive of Public History in the Twenty-First Century,” portrays the creation of the 1821 Greek Revolution Observatory, a digital project commemorating the bicentennial of the Greek Revolution. The authors involved in the project aimed at helping the public effectively engage with the “historical culture” of the various groups that use the Revolution in discourses about identify formation. Accordingly, the authors used the digital project to reflect viewpoints of academic historians, national and local institutions, artists and the Internet to bring into conversation with each other the ways in which Greeks have used the past across history to define themselves and respond to new challenges.</p> <p>The fourth and fifth articles depart from the digital archive theme to show historians engaging with the public in new ways. In “We and Bobby Lee: Public Historians and the Fight to Remove Confederate Memorials”, the authors use their expertise and access to academic material to provide input over the 2021 campaign to rename Robert E. Lee Middle School in San Marcos, Texas. While admitting their status as locals and “white males” helped them state their case to the school board, I appreciated how effective producing historical facts targeting common narratives and sharing how certain historiographical perspectives were weaponized in certain political moments were to convincing the proper authorities and producing positive change. In “Busy Being Born: A Brief History of the Museum of Pop Culture”, the author describes the creation of the Museum of Pop Culture in Seattle, Washington, arguing that the singular vision of Paul Allen as founder allowed the museum to set an example for non-traditional museums of the future and intervene in cultural discourse in ways more collectively-funded projects could not. Written by a former employee of Paul Allen’s Vulcan Foundation and engaging in typical hagiographic discourse around tech “visionaries,” this article felt below the standards of an academic article and, against its best attempts, showed the museum to be plagued by a lack of unity, denigration of countercultural stakeholders, and funding challenges.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="sample-posts"/><category term="formatting"/><category term="links"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Review of The Public Historian vol. 45, no. 4 (November 2023) issue on digital archives.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Introducing Public History - ch. 5-8</title><link href="https://cxdomi.github.io/blog/2024/iph-response2/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Introducing Public History - ch. 5-8"/><published>2024-09-30T18:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-09-30T18:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://cxdomi.github.io/blog/2024/iph-response2</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://cxdomi.github.io/blog/2024/iph-response2/"><![CDATA[<p>Introducing Public History: Interpreting the Past, Engaging Audiences. Lyon, Nix, and Shrum. Lanham, MD: Rowman &amp; Littlefield, 2017.</p> <p>In the fifth chapter, “Interpreting and Exhibiting History,” the authors describe the components involved in developing exhibits, from choosing the “Big Idea” that guides its creation, to curating historical objects and producing the exhibit labels that accompany each object and section, to developing relationships with and collaborating with the relevant stakeholders before, during and after each project. In the sixth and seventh chapters (“Engaging Audiences” and “Engaging Audiences: Case Studies from the Field”), the authors cover the diversity of methods public historians can choose to present history to audiences, whether via more traditional interpretive techniques such as tour guides or more interactive forms of engagement like living history museums that allow visitors to participate in historical activities, and lay out how to strategically introduce more difficult encounters to the public in productive, meaningful ways. The final chapter, “Putting Public History to Work in Your World,” gives three examples of possible career paths those interested in public history can pursue, including roles with city governments, heritage centers, and archives.</p> <p>Though these final chapters do a fine job in further elaborating the expectations to which public historians should hold themselves within the authors’ stated framework of “progressive public history,” one begins to wonder whether this book embodies a sense of optimism, emblematic of the height of the Obama era, that underestimated the extent the challenge in helping the public connect to their history would increase as American society has become more polarized and more suspicious of institutions at large. As suggested by their inclusion of the “Standards for Museum Exhibits Dealing with Historical Subjects,” the exhibits we design should deploy historical knowledge to enrich “the context in which citizens make informed decisions” in a democracy and “assist individuals in identifying commonalities in the human condition and in negotiating the differences that exist in our increasingly pluralistic world” (105). While I personally agree fully with these stated goals, how do public historians account for a growing segment of the public that no longer believes in the possibility of a society built around pluralist aspirations, and that is increasingly pessimistic about our ability to publicly deliberate our collective choices, regardless of how much knowledge we provide? The authors seem to have faith in the public historian’s ability to play cultural psychologist and help repair our collective psyche by “complicat[ing] narratives” (118), producing “discomfort zones” to encourage difficult encounters (124), and “asking the public to solve today’s problems” (120). I feel this activist approach may take for granted the stability of the public’s trust in museums, which stems less from how much they uphold certain democratic values than in how museums empower visitors to encounter history on their own terms. That said, it’s clear from the book that this has been an obstacle for some time: in chapter six, the authors present the case study of Colonial Williamsburg, where actors simulated a slave auction for visitors in 1994. While the auction was meant to engage the discomfort of visitors around the reality of the site’s history of slavery, some visitors of color felt the program was insensitive, which “might have educated white visitors, but could have added to the burden of the history of slavery for black visitors” (127). Despite the best intentions of the curators and actors, the program ended for good that same year.</p> <p>How should public historians account for the increasing suspicion engendered among the public towards our profession? Should we recognize the limits to what the profession can achieve, and urge even more caution in how we define our projects? Or should we be doing more political work to align stakeholders, and collaborate with other activist professions to engender less suspicious and more pluralistic-oriented publics? I still believe using public history to encourage pluralism is possible and necessary, but it may require more work in understanding public history’s place in the wider ecosystem of knowledge, more strategic analysis on how we plan out our work, and more creativity in tackling social and political obstacles that may threaten the public’s trust in our work.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="sample-posts"/><category term="formatting"/><category term="links"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[Introducing Public History: Interpreting the Past, Engaging Audiences. Lyon, Nix, and Shrum. Lanham, MD: Rowman &amp; Littlefield, 2017.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Introducing Public History - ch.1-4</title><link href="https://cxdomi.github.io/blog/2024/iph-response1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Introducing Public History - ch.1-4"/><published>2024-09-16T18:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-09-16T18:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://cxdomi.github.io/blog/2024/iph-response1</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://cxdomi.github.io/blog/2024/iph-response1/"><![CDATA[<p>Introducing Public History: Interpreting the Past, Engaging Audiences. Lyon, Nix, and Shrum. Lanham, MD: Rowman &amp; Littlefield, 2017.</p> <p>In the first chapter, entitled “Introducing Public History”, the authors draw a distinction between traditional academic history and public history, presenting the latter as a discipline that emphasizes its relation to its audience, stakeholders, and ethical responsibilities. In the second chapter, entitled “Thinking Historically”, the authors introduce the concept of “history as a practice” to describe both the work that public historians do as historians and the ways of thinking they should instill in their audiences through their public history work. In the third chapter, entitled “Interpreting the Past Case Study: The Baltimore ’68 Project”, the authors dissect the elements of a successful public history project, the Baltimore ‘ 68 project commemorating the fortieth anniversary of the 1968 Baltimore unrest, highlighting what they call a “Community-based participatory research” approach to shared historical authority and an example of “reflective practice.” In the fourth chapter, entitled “Collecting History”, the authors share a history of collections management and share methods and considerations that account for the difficulties of building collections that represent historically under-represented populations.</p> <p>My biggest takeaway from these chapters is a reorientation of the purpose of public history from merely providing the public access to historical knowledge towards promoting the idea of “thinking historically, asking questions about the past, and exploring how history relates to our lives” (29). I generally agree with the book’s stated “progressive public history” approach, particularly as a project that aims to “harness the innate sense people already have of themselves as historical interpreters, working with them to uncover liberatory tools in their lives, communities, and nations” (x). In my view, history is not just a body of knowledge but a framework in which individuals and communities come to recognize the presence of power in how they organize their lives, understand themselves, and relate to others. Public historians serve a fundamental allyship role in this regard, acting as experts in producing historical knowledge, as liaisons between the academic discipline and those outside of the academy, and tacticians who can equip the public with the historical tools and help guide them strategically in deploying these tools so they can become self-conscious agents in their own histories.</p> <p>The third and fourth chapters were particular instructive in providing examples of how public history can work to promote broader liberatory goals. In the case of the Baltimore ’68 project, the lack of a clear historical record of the 1968 unrest was seen by Baltimoreans as both a symptom and a cause of the racialized underdevelopment of the city, prompting public historians to intervene, not only to commemorate the anniversary, but to “remove a stumbling block to future civic progress” (34). In interviewing participants and witnesses to the unrest, public historians simultaneously produced new primary sources to the event, giving Baltimoreans an opportunity to reconsider the significance of the unrest and challenge its popular representations, and repaired the distrust that had affected the relationship between the community and the university. Having contributed to developing a healthier understanding of their past, the Baltimore ’68 project primed the community to become more responsive to the 2015 unrest after the murder of Freddie Gray. A similar project, the Smithsonian’s 2004 Latinos and Baseball collecting initiative, used community-based collecting to produce an opportunity for the Latino community to rally around their memories of a event that contributed to their cultural unity, helping them to revisit its significance to their history and reinforce their pride in their values. Both instances demonstrate the importance of encouraging “history as a practice.”</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="sample-posts"/><category term="formatting"/><category term="links"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[march & april, looking forward to summer]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Google Gemini updates: Flash 1.5, Gemma 2 and Project Astra</title><link href="https://cxdomi.github.io/blog/2024/google-gemini-updates-flash-15-gemma-2-and-project-astra/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Google Gemini updates: Flash 1.5, Gemma 2 and Project Astra"/><published>2024-05-14T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2024-05-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>https://cxdomi.github.io/blog/2024/google-gemini-updates-flash-15-gemma-2-and-project-astra</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://cxdomi.github.io/blog/2024/google-gemini-updates-flash-15-gemma-2-and-project-astra/"><![CDATA[]]></content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"><![CDATA[We’re sharing updates across our Gemini family of models and a glimpse of Project Astra, our vision for the future of AI assistants.]]></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Displaying External Posts on Your al-folio Blog</title><link href="https://cxdomi.github.io/blog/2022/displaying-external-posts-on-your-al-folio-blog/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Displaying External Posts on Your al-folio Blog"/><published>2022-04-23T23:20:09+00:00</published><updated>2022-04-23T23:20:09+00:00</updated><id>https://cxdomi.github.io/blog/2022/displaying-external-posts-on-your-al-folio-blog</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://cxdomi.github.io/blog/2022/displaying-external-posts-on-your-al-folio-blog/"><![CDATA[]]></content><author><name></name></author></entry><entry><title type="html">a post with formatting and links</title><link href="https://cxdomi.github.io/blog/2015/formatting-and-links/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="a post with formatting and links"/><published>2015-03-15T16:40:16+00:00</published><updated>2015-03-15T16:40:16+00:00</updated><id>https://cxdomi.github.io/blog/2015/formatting-and-links</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://cxdomi.github.io/blog/2015/formatting-and-links/"><![CDATA[<p>Jean shorts raw denim Vice normcore, art party High Life PBR skateboard stumptown vinyl kitsch. Four loko meh 8-bit, tousled banh mi tilde forage Schlitz dreamcatcher twee 3 wolf moon. Chambray asymmetrical paleo salvia, sartorial umami four loko master cleanse drinking vinegar brunch. <a href="https://www.pinterest.com">Pinterest</a> DIY authentic Schlitz, hoodie Intelligentsia butcher trust fund brunch shabby chic Kickstarter forage flexitarian. Direct trade <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Cold-pressed_juice">cold-pressed</a> meggings stumptown plaid, pop-up taxidermy. Hoodie XOXO fingerstache scenester Echo Park. Plaid ugh Wes Anderson, freegan pug selvage fanny pack leggings pickled food truck DIY irony Banksy.</p> <h4 id="hipster-list">Hipster list</h4> <ul> <li>brunch</li> <li>fixie</li> <li>raybans</li> <li>messenger bag</li> </ul> <h4 id="check-list">Check List</h4> <ul class="task-list"> <li class="task-list-item"><input type="checkbox" class="task-list-item-checkbox" disabled="disabled" checked="checked"/>Brush Teeth</li> <li class="task-list-item"><input type="checkbox" class="task-list-item-checkbox" disabled="disabled"/>Put on socks <ul class="task-list"> <li class="task-list-item"><input type="checkbox" class="task-list-item-checkbox" disabled="disabled" checked="checked"/>Put on left sock</li> <li class="task-list-item"><input type="checkbox" class="task-list-item-checkbox" disabled="disabled"/>Put on right sock</li> </ul> </li> <li class="task-list-item"><input type="checkbox" class="task-list-item-checkbox" disabled="disabled" checked="checked"/>Go to school</li> </ul> <p>Hoodie Thundercats retro, tote bag 8-bit Godard craft beer gastropub. Truffaut Tumblr taxidermy, raw denim Kickstarter sartorial dreamcatcher. Quinoa chambray slow-carb salvia readymade, bicycle rights 90’s yr typewriter selfies letterpress cardigan vegan.</p> <hr/> <p>Pug heirloom High Life vinyl swag, single-origin coffee four dollar toast taxidermy reprehenderit fap distillery master cleanse locavore. Est anim sapiente leggings Brooklyn ea. Thundercats locavore excepteur veniam eiusmod. Raw denim Truffaut Schlitz, migas sapiente Portland VHS twee Bushwick Marfa typewriter retro id keytar.</p> <blockquote> <p>We do not grow absolutely, chronologically. We grow sometimes in one dimension, and not in another, unevenly. We grow partially. We are relative. We are mature in one realm, childish in another. —Anais Nin</p> </blockquote> <p>Fap aliqua qui, scenester pug Echo Park polaroid irony shabby chic ex cardigan church-key Odd Future accusamus. Blog stumptown sartorial squid, gastropub duis aesthetic Truffaut vero. Pinterest tilde twee, odio mumblecore jean shorts lumbersexual.</p>]]></content><author><name></name></author><category term="sample-posts"/><category term="formatting"/><category term="links"/><summary type="html"><![CDATA[march & april, looking forward to summer]]></summary></entry></feed>